{"tossups": [{"question": "An exhibition by an artist from this country saw the ceiling, walls, and floors of a gallery covered with meaningless text. In addition to Book from the Sky, a 2008 exhibition by an artist from this country lined the Tate Modern art gallery with porcelain sunflower seeds. The long, twisted steel of this country\u2019s National Stadium earned it the nickname \u201cthe (*) Bird\u2019s Nest.\u201d This country is home to the Suzhou Museum, a building designed by the architect of the Hancock Tower and a famous glass pyramid. For 10 points, name this birth country of Xu Bing, Ai Weiwei, and I. M. Pei.", "answer": "People's Republic of China (accept PRC, do not accept \u201cRepublic of China\u201d)", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Cells that contain this molecule include the A9 dopaminergic neurons in the substantia nigra, alveolar cells, and mesangial cells in the kidney. This protein is found in all vertebrates, except for the fish family Channichthyidae. The amount of this protein is quantified using Drabkin's reagent. An abnormality in the production of this molecule is known as (*) thalassemia. This protein\u2019s obstructed function in acidic conditions is called the Bohr Effect. The active component of this protein contains four porphyrin rings that surround a central iron atom. For ten points, name this protein that carries oxygen in red blood cells.", "answer": "hemoglobin", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One painting by this artist has a section of black down the middle with the rest of the canvas mostly white with yellow and is entitled The Deep. This man\u2019s Mural on Indian Red Ground was confiscated by the Iranian government after his death. Because of its 8 colored lines, this artist\u2019s Number 11, 1952 is also called (*) \u201cBlue Poles\u201d. A line from The Tempest lends its name to his Full Fathom Five, and this man\u2019s Number 1, 1950 is more commonly called \u201cLavender Mist.\u201d For 10 points, name this abstract expressionist artist whose \u201caction painting\u201d earned him the nickname \u201cthe Dripper.\u201d", "answer": "Jackson Pollock", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "The Festival of Carneia limited the forces of this battle\u2019s winning side, who lost only 192 men in the fight. The inciting conflict of this battle included the Sack of Sardis and was crushed at the Battle of Lade. Hippias lost a tooth in the lead-up to this battle, which saw Cynaegirus die while pulling a fleeing (*) trireme back toward the beach. Miltiades\u2019 decision to extend the Athenian line contributed to his victory over a larger Persian army in this battle. For ten points, name this 490 BC battle whose outcome Pheidippides ran 26.2 miles to announce.", "answer": "Battle of Marathon", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One poem by this poet states, \u201cOne must have a mind of winter to regard the frost and the boughs.\u201d That poem is \u201cThe Snow Man.\u201d This poet once said that the title object of another poem \u201cwas gray and bare,\u201d and after he had placed that object in Tennessee, this poet said that \u201cIt took (*) dominion everywhere.\u201d Another poem by this man states that \u201cIt was evening all afternoon. It was snowing.\u201d For ten points, name this poet who wrote \u201cThe Anecdote of the Jar\u201d and \u201cThirteen Ways of Looking at a Blackbird.\u201d", "answer": "Wallace Stevens", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This woman purchased land in Auburn, New York which became her base of activity. This woman suffered seizures and visions after being hit in the head with an iron weight as a child, and while serving as a scout for the Union Army, this woman guided an 1863 raid at Combahee Ferry. In 2016, Treasury Secretary Jack (*) Lew announced that this woman would replace Andrew Jackson on the front of the $20 bill. For ten points, name this Maryland suffragist, abolitionist and Underground Railroad conductor called the \u201cMoses of her People\u201d who personally rescued over 100 slaves.", "answer": "Harriet Tubman", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One type of this particle would create long-range fluctuations with little energy cost, according to the Mermin\u2013Wagner theorem. In theories with gauge symmetry, one type of this particle becomes massive and is longitudinally polarized by the (*) \u201cGoldstone\u201d variety of this particle. BCS theory describes superconductivity as caused by the condensation of Cooper pairs, which behave like these particles. The weak interaction is mediated by the W+, W-, and Z0 subtypes of these elementary particles, which have integer spin. For 10 points, name this particle whose \u201cHiggs\u201d variety is responsible for mass.", "answer": "boson", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In the final scene of this play, the protagonist says that she has survived by \u201cperforming tricks\u201d all her life. Another character in this play, Mrs. Linde, explains that she had to care for her sick mother and brothers. The protagonist of this play (*) borrowed money from a man called \u201cmorally sick\u201d by Dr. Rank, Krogstad, in order to finance a trip to Italy, and is blackmailed by Krogstad so he can keep his job at the bank where the protagonist\u2019s husband, Torvald, works. For ten points, name this play that ends with Nora Helmer slamming the door behind her, written by Henrik Ibsen.", "answer": "A Doll\u2019s House", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One of these creatures in Greek mythology created the Hippocrene fountains that would give the Muses poetic inspiration. Heimdall owns one of these creatures called Gulltopr, and another one of these is given as a gift from Thor and is named Gullfaxi. One of these creatures helped to build the walls of Asgard, and another one of these animals was attacked by a (*) gadfly when it tried to ascend Mount Olympus. A giant wooden version of one of these animals was constructed to allow soldiers to enter Troy. For 10 points, name these animals, an eight-legged example of which is Odin\u2019s Sleipnir.", "answer": "horses (accept Pegasus before Heimdall)", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology"}, {"question": "An algorithm for the minimization of this quantity is used with the Peng\u2013Robinson Equation to model water-gas shift reactions. The residual of this quantity divided by RT is the natural logarithm of the fugacity coefficient. Taking the partial derivative of this quantity with respect to the mole fraction yields (*) chemical potential, and the change in this quantity is the negative product of RT and the natural logarithm of the equilibrium constant. This quantity is equal to enthalpy minus the product of entropy and temperature. For 10 points, name this quantity, used to predict the spontaneity of a reaction.", "answer": "Gibbs free energy (prompt on \u201cfree energy\u201d and \u201cenergy\u201d) HALFTIME", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One of this author\u2019s works begins in the town Plassans with the matriarch of the title family, Adelaide Fouque. The youngest branch of the family is the Mourets, the middle class people and the children of Ursule Macquart. The high born branch of the family is the Rougons, who are the focus of his first and last books of the series, La Fortune des Rougon and Le Docteur Pascal. This practitioner of (*) naturalism also wrote a newspaper article criticizing the French government\u2019s handling of treason accusations against Jewish artillery officer Alfred Dreyfus. For ten points, name this author of J\u2019accuse.", "answer": "\u00c9mile Zola", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The binomial type of this construct makes merging two of these very efficient. Algorithms that make use of this structure include Prim\u2019s algorithm and Dijkstra\u2019s algorithm, which uses the Fibonacci variety of this construct to efficiently find the shortest path between two nodes of a graph. This data structure is an implementation of a (*) priority queue, and in its namesake sorting algorithm, the elements of a list are successively inserted into one of these and then popped, yielding a worst-case runtime of O(n log n) [O of n log n]. For 10 points, name this tree-like data structure in which nodes are always greater or always less than their children.", "answer": "heap", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In this novel, one character explains to the main character \u201cClock time is nothing where art is concerned\u201d when asked why he wakes up so early. A Jehovah\u2019s Witness in this novel threatens to castrate himself to prove that he did not rape a girl, and a writer who was hired by Genaro eventually kills all of his characters in a fire. This novel\u2019s odd chapters take place in (*) Radio Panamericana, while the even chapters follow the fictional characters created by Pedro Comacho. For ten points, name this novel about Mario Varguitas and his romance with the title relative, written by Mario Vargas Llosa.", "answer": "Aunt Julia and the Scriptwriter", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This composer used the violin piece Salut D\u2019amour as an engagement present. The Angel of Agony visits a man known as \u201cthe Soul\u201d as he travels through Purgatory in an oratorio by this man. Jacqueline du Pre famously recorded his Cello Concerto in E minor, and Edward VII was the dedicatee of a work by this man which later included (*) \u201cThe Land of Hope and Glory\u201d. This composer used names like \u201cDorabella\u201d for movements in one work, in addition to a section dedicated to his editor entitled \u201cNimrod\u201d. For 10 points, name this English composer of The Dream of Gerontius, Enigma Variations, and Pomp and Circumstance.", "answer": "Edward Elgar", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "These people launched a short-lived 1815 uprising at Slachter's Nek. These people triumphed at the Battle of Blood River during the Great Trek, and later instigated the Maritz Rebellion at the beginning of World War One. The Jameson Raid began one conflict targeting these people, during which (*) Horatio Kitchener imprisoned many of these people in concentration camps. These people made up the Orange Free State and Transvaal, the latter of which was led by Paul Kruger. For ten points, name these ethnic Dutch settlers of South Africa who fought two namesake wars against Britain.", "answer": "Boers (accept Afrikaners or Trekboer before \u201cnamesake\u201d is read)", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "The sky god of this religion used his 7,000 coils to form the stars and the planets, and he shed a snake skin to create the waters of Earth. That god\u2019s name is Damballah. Temples of this religion are called Hounfours, and priests in this religion are variably called (*) houngans and mambos depending on their gender. Gods of this religion include Simbi, Kouzin Zaka, Papa Legba, and Bondye and are typically referred to as loa. For 10 points, name this syncretic religion common in Haiti, associated with mystic dolls that share its name.", "answer": "Voodoo (accept Haitian Vodou, Vodun, Vod\u00fa, or Vud\u00fa)", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion"}, {"question": "The music video for this song takes place at the bar La Factor\u00eda. This song bested a notable record set by Mariah Carey\u2019s \u201cOne Sweet Day,\u201d while Sesame Street parodied this song as a ballad about a rubber ducky. The success of this single made featured rapper (*) Daddy Yankee the most listened to artist in the world in June 2017. Justin Bieber created a wildly popular remix of this song, but was criticized for struggling with its Spanish lyrics in performances. For ten points, name this 2017 pop song by Luis Fonsi, the most streamed song of all time.", "answer": "\u201cDespacito\u201d", "category": "Trash", "subcategory": "Trash"}, {"question": "This thinker was passed over for a major promotion in favor of Ralph Linton. In one work, this author of Tales of the Cochiti Indians borrowed a Nietzschean dichotomy to describe the Zuni, Dobu, and Pueblo peoples. With Gene Weltfish, this person theorized about cultural and moral relativism in a pamphlet for American soldiers entitled \u201cThe (*) Races of Mankind.\u201d In another work, this woman used \u201canthropology at a distance\u201d to contrast guilt and shame cultures during World War Two. For ten points, name this anthropologist and student of Franz Boas who wrote Patterns of Culture and The Chrysanthemum and the Sword.", "answer": "Ruth Benedict", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science"}, {"question": "Charles Marie de La Condamine led the first major exploration of this river and the city of Bel\u00e9m is located where this river reaches the ocean. Though originally known by the name of its main source river, the Mara\u00f1\u00f3n, this river received its contemporary name after Spanish conquistadors battled a band of female (*) warriors along its banks. One state named for this river has its capital at Manaus, while spider monkeys and many varieties of tree frog can be found in its namesake rainforest. For ten points, name this great river of South America, the second longest in the world.", "answer": "Amazon River", "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography"}, {"question": "Edward Mylius libeled one king of this name as a bigamist. Viscount Stanhope was a minister for one king with this name, and another attempted to pass the Pains and Penalties Bill to divorce his wife, Caroline of Brunswick. One king with this name survived the Forty-Five Jacobite Rising, and was the final monarch of his country to (*) lead troops in battle. The American Declaration of Independence criticizes one king of this name. For ten points, give this name of six British monarchs as well as the eldest son of Prince William and Kate Middleton.", "answer": "George", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One of these objects in Chilote mythology is called Caleuche and is watched over by the \u201csirena chilota.\u201d Atet is one of these objects in Egyptian mythology, and it is used by Ra when fighting the serpent Apep. Another one of these objects was constructed using timber that could speak and make (*) prophecies. Gilgamesh\u2019s relative Utnapishtim uses one of these called the \u201cPreserver of Life\u201d to save himself and the animals. For 10 points, name these vessels used for transport on water, examples of which include the Argo and Noah\u2019s Ark.", "answer": "ships (accept boats or arks before reading, accept barge after \u2018Atet\u2019) Bonuses", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "The motivating fear behind this policy was spurred by the Niihau Incident. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Japanese Internment", "Korematsu vs U.S.", "Nisei"], "parts": ["Name this American policy during World War Two which confined members of certain ethnic group to various relocation camps.", "Japanese internment was unsuccessfully challenged in this 1944 court case. In a 6-3 decision, the Supreme Court ruled that the need for national security trumped the plaintiff\u2019s individual rights.", "This term describes second generation Japanese Americans, including Fred Korematsu. Despite the injustice of internment, many members of this group served in the U.S. military."], "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "This man defeated a fire-breathing goblin named Aillen by holding a spear to his forehead, allowing him to resist a sleep-inducing song. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Finn Mac Cumaill (pronounced \u2018Finn MacCool\u2019)", "Fenian Cycle (accept Ossian Cycle)", "Oisin (pronounced \u2018Usheen\u2019)"], "parts": ["Name this warrior figure of Celtic mythology who lead the Fianna after ousting the traitor Goll Mac Morna.", "Finn Mac Cumaill is the hero of this cycle of Irish mythology, often compared to the Ulster, Invasions, and Historical cycles.", "This man is the primary narrator of the Fenian Cycle. This son of Finn Mac Cumaill fell off of his horse while on his way to visit his father, trapping him outside of the Land of Youth forever."], "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "The use of these numbers is very important in computer graphics when rotating three-dimensional objects. For ten points each:", "answers": ["quaternions", "William Rowan Hamilton", "bridges"], "parts": ["Name these four-dimensional numbers that take the form a+bi+cj+dk that, unlike the complex numbers, lack the commutative property.", "Quaternions were introduced by this Irish mathematician in 1843. With Arthur Cayley, he names a theorem stating that every square matrix over a commutative ring satisfies its own characteristic equation.", "When the equation that i-squared, j-squared, k-squared, and ijk equals negative one occurred to Hamilton, he could not resist carving it on one of these structures."], "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Saint James the Moor-slayer led Asturian troops in the early phase of this conflict. For ten points each:", "answers": ["La Reconquista", "Isabella I of Castile and Ferdinand II of Aragon", "Emir Muhammad XII (accept Boabdil)"], "parts": ["Name this 700 year period in which Christian forces gradually reclaimed the Iberian peninsula from Muslim kingdoms.", "These two Catholic monarchs completed Reconquista in 1492 after conquering Granada. That same year, the duo funded an expedition led by Christopher Columbus.", "This final Muslim ruler in Spain attempted to live out his days peacefully, but like many Spanish Muslims, oppressive Christian rule led him to emigrate."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "A metastable state is one of these quantum states. For ten points each:", "answers": ["excited state", "laser (accept light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation)", "gain medium (accept gain media, active laser media, or lasing media)"], "parts": ["Name this state of a system that has higher energy than a ground state.", "More members of a system are in excited states when population inversion occurs, which is necessary in these devices. Theodore Maiman built one of these devices using a ruby crystal.", "This type of material has quantum properties that allow it to amplify laser beams. It is excited by a pump source."], "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "After the 1911 Agadir Crisis, this nation became a French protectorate. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Kingdom of Morocco", "Almoravid Dynasty", "Western Sahara"], "parts": ["Name this North African country whose capital city is Rabat.", "Morocco was home to this powerful medieval dynasty, based in Marrakesh and with dominions extending from Spain to Mauretania.", "Since 1975, the Moroccan Army has sporadically battled the Polisario Front for control of this disputed desert region along the Atlantic coast."], "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "The death of the main character in this novel is marked by the chapter \u201cVanished into the clouds,\u201d consisting of no text. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Tale of Genji", "Lady Murasaki Shikibu", "Lady Fujitsubo"], "parts": ["Name this extensive work about the life of the son of Emperor Kiritsubo as he rises and falls through the ranks of court and womanizes incessantly.", "This lady-in-waiting wrote The Tale of Genji.", "This is the name of Genji\u2019s first love. He later trains one of her relatives, a girl named Murasaki, to be exactly like her."], "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "These entities are classified as s, p, d, or f depending on their angular momentum quantum number. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["atomic orbitals (prompt on \u201celectron orbital\u201d and \u201corbital,\u201d do not accept \u201cmolecular orbital\u201d or \u201cshell\u201d)", "sp3 hybridization", "bond order"], "parts": ["Name these entities that can contain a maximum of two electrons.", "The mixing of atomic orbitals leads to hybridization into hybrid orbitals with different energies. Methane has this hybridization because it is tetrahedral and has formula CH4.", "Molecular orbital theory can also be used to determine molecular structures. In MO theory, this quantity is defined as the number of bonding electrons minus the number of antibonding electrons divided by 2."], "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This book closes with a plea to \u201cfear God, and keep his commandments: for this is the whole duty of man.\u201d For ten points each:", "answers": ["Book of Ecclesiastes", "time", "St. Thomas Aquinas"], "parts": ["Name this book of the Bible in which a wise teacher ponders the meaning of life.", "In one of Ecclesiastes most notable sections, the Teacher asserts that there is one of these concepts for \u201cevery purpose under heaven,\u201d including one to be born, one to die, one to weep, and one to laugh.", "This thinker cited Ecclesiastes\u2019 claim that the \u201cnumber of fools is infinite\u201d when discussing the quantity of good and evil in his Summa Theologica."], "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "This character gives birth to a boy named Wade Hampton and a girl named Ella Lorena and marries three times during the course of the novel she appears in. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Scarlett O\u2019Hara (accept either)", "Gone with the Wind", "the Ku Klux Klan (accept KKK)"], "parts": ["Name this southern belle who marries a wealthy blockade runner and manages Tara Plantation.", "This is the novel that Scarlett appears in, a Margaret Mitchell novel set during and after the American Civil War.", "In Gone with the Wind, Melanie explains that Scarlett\u2019s husbands are all a part of this group, whose activities lead to the death of Frank Kennedy."], "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about important locations along the Appalachian Mountain Range. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Maine", "Blue Ridge Mountains", "Clingman\u2019s Dome"], "parts": ["The trail begins at Mount Katahdin in this New England state which also contains Acadia National Park.", "The Appalachian Trail passes through these mountains named for their coloration when viewed from a distance. A parkway through these mountains is the most visited part of the National Park Service.", "The Great Smoky Mountains, a subrange of the Blue Ridge, contain this peak, the highest point on the Appalachian Trail."], "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "This man\u2019s strait-laced character and suffix earned him the ironic nickname \u201cBobby Three Sticks.\u201d For ten points each:", "answers": ["Robert Mueller III", "Paul Manafort", "Ty Cobb"], "parts": ["Name this former Director of the FBI and Special Counsel investigating Russian interference in the 2016 U.S. presidential election.", "In October 2017, Mueller\u2019s team indicted this man on charges of money laundering. This lobbyist is accused of masking millions of dollars in payments from the Ukrainian government.", "This man serves as the White House\u2019s lead attorney in matters relating to Mueller\u2019s investigation. This man shares his name with a former Detroit Tigers second baseman."], "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Sadly, the phenomenon of civil war persists in the modern era. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Syria", "Yemen", "Tamil"], "parts": ["This Middle Eastern nation has endured a bloody civil war since 2011, pitting dictator Bashar al-Assad, resistance fighters, ISIS, and the Kurdish Rojava against each other.", "This Middle Eastern country is also embroiled in civil war, with former President Abdrabbuh Mansur Hadi and his Saudi allies clashing with former President Ali Abdullah Saleh and his Iran-backed Houthi allies.", "Though long running civil war in Sri Lanka ended in 2009, tensions remain between the Sri Lankan government and this ethnic group whose \u201cLiberation Tigers\u201d were defeated in the brutal conflict."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For ten points each, name these novels set during epidemics.", "answers": ["Death in Venice", "The Plague", "A Journal of the Plague Year"], "parts": ["This Thomas Mann novella follows the ascetic Gustav von Aschenbach\u2019s infatuation with Tadzio in a cholera-ridden Italian city.", "This novel by Albert Camus takes place in the French-Algerian city of Oran and features characters like Cottard and Dr. Castel.", "Daniel Defoe recounted a disease stricken London in this novel, which he published under a pseudonym to hide his age when the outbreak actually occurred."], "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about George Bernard Shaw\u2019s play <em>Pygmalion</em>. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Eliza Doolittle (accept either)", "Covent Garden", "My Fair Lady"], "parts": ["This character in Pygmalion learns elocution from Professor Henry Higgins, eventually passing off as a high society lady.", "This location is where Eliza works as a Cockney flower girl and meets the professor.", "Pygmalion was adapted into this long-running Lerner and Loewe musical. Rex Harrison and Julie Andrews starred in this show\u2019s original run."], "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "The facial features of characters in this painting were inspired by African masks. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Les Demoiselles d'Avignon", "Barcelona", "Opening of the Fifth Seal"], "parts": ["Name this 1907 Pablo Picasso painting depicting five prostitutes in a brothel.", "Les Demoiselles d'Avignon is set in this Spanish city whose Museu Picasso maintains the largest collection of Picasso works in the world.", "Les Demoiselles d'Avignon was partially inspired by this El Greco painting which shows St. John with outstretched arms looking a several nude people."], "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "This work begins with the melody of the Troparion of the Holy Cross. At the turning point of this work, <em>God Save the Tsar</em> plays over <em>La Marseillaise</em>. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The 1812 Overture (accept The Year 1812)", "Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky", "\u201cFate Motif\u201d"], "parts": ["Name this work commemorating the defense of Russia from Napoleon\u2019s invading Grand Armee, complete with cannon fire.", "This composer of The Nutcracker and Swan Lake also wrote the 1812 Overture.", "This term describes an A-flat phrase in Tchaikovsky\u2019s Symphony No. 4. This terms also refers to a section that opens Shostakovich\u2019s 8th Symphony."], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "In this work, its author expresses pride that he \u201cdid not make proof of my virility before the proper season.\u201d For ten points each:", "answers": ["Meditations", "a good person (or good man, or descriptive equivalents)", "Stoicism"], "parts": ["Name this diary of personal reflections and self-improvement compiled by the Roman emperor Marcus Aurelius. This text urges its reader not to \u201cact as if you were going to live ten thousand years.\u201d", "In Meditations, Marcus discourages the discussion of what makes up this concept and instead urges the reader to just be one.", "Meditations aligns with this school of philosophy founded by Zeno and known for its foundational logic and dismissal of emotions. The works of Seneca the Younger also express this philosophy."], "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy"}, {"leadin": "This ancient Athenian artist had a favorite model named Phryne. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Praxiteles", "Hermes with the Infant Dionysus", "Apollo"], "parts": ["Name this sculptor of The Resting Satyr and The Aberdeen Head.", "This sculpture by Praxiteles features a Greek god balancing a small baby in his hand. The arm missing from this sculpture was likely holding grapes.", "Praxiteles created multiple sculptures of this God, including Lycian and Sauroktonos versions. Depictions of this god often show him playing a lute or slaying Python."], "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "This technique was developed by Kary Mullis and includes denaturation, annealing, and extension steps. For ten points each:", "answers": ["PCR (accept polymerase chain reaction)", "CRISPR (accept clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats)", "Cas9 (accept CRISPR associated protein 9)"], "parts": ["Name this procedure used to amplify segments of DNA.", "This is another biological technique using DNA. It is a genome editing technology adapted from a prokaryotic defense system.", "The CRISPR immunity system in Streptococcus pyogenes is related to this protein. It is used to create a double stranded break in foreign DNA."], "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "One movement of this piece uses a xylophone to evoke the image of skeletons playing cards. Another movement includes \u201chopping\u201d fifths preceded by grace notes. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Carnival of the Animals", "Tortoises", "The Dying Swan"], "parts": ["Name this suite by Camille Saint-Saens that includes movements such as Fossils, and Kangaroos.", "This movement of The Carnival of the Animals uses a very slow version of the \u201cGalop Infernal,\u201d often called the Can-Can.", "This ballet was choreographed by Mikhail Fokine on the movement \u201cLe Cygne.\u201d It was performed by Anna Pavlova 4,000 times."], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}]}